Hello, English learners. Welcome back to another
lesson with us here at English pod. My name
is Marco and I'm Erica and today we have a
lesson for all our university students out there.
That's right. We're talking
about registering for university.
Okay, so it's a difficult process sometimes
even in your own language. So we're going to try
and make it a little bit easier by giving you
some of the common words that you would need.
To register at a university. Alright, well, I
think it's time we get started by listening to the
dialogue and we're going to listen to a young
female student as she tries to choose her classes.
Excuse me, is this
where I register?
I'd like to sign up for my
courses for next semester.
Yes, of course. I need your student ID please.
Here you are. Okay, Susan. It says here that
you are a business major and that you're in
your second year. Is this information correct?
Yes, I do want to take some additional credits
this year to get a minor in psychology. Sure,
that's not a problem. Do you have a list of
courses that you want to take this semester?
Yeah, here's my list.
I'm not sure if the class
schedule allowed me to
take all of them though.
Yeah, that's perfect. What about the
subjects for your minor? Oh yeah, I almost
forgot. I need to take fundamental linguistics,
consumer psychology, and neuro anatomy.
Wow, you're going to be busy this semester.
Okay, here you go.
You're registered now.
You have to make your first
tuition payment before classes start.
All right, great. A very good student
taking a lot of classes this semester.
I know, and it sounds like some
of them are pretty hard as well.
Yeah, they are. Well, she
used some of those very
common phrases that we
would need when we are
registering at university. So let's take a
look at them now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay, so the first thing, I
think we need to deal
with this word to register.
Register. So register for university. Okay,
so we've mentioned this word many times.
So I think it would be a
good idea to listen to some
examples and then we'll
come back and explain it.
Example one.
I registered to attend the conference
on international trade this month.
Example two.
It is your obligation as a
good citizen to register to vote.
Example three.
It is necessary to register on our
website before joining the conference.
So when you register for
something, you put your
name down on a list,
right? So in this case,
when you register for
university, you put your
you officially put your
name on the list of
students in that course. Okay,
so you can register for university.
What else can you register for?
Register for a class. You can even
register to vote. Okay, so register.
Now she was
registering for her classes.
And we saw these words
that we know already,
but but it's a good idea
to take a look at them.
We heard that she
is a business major.
So a major, a major business major.
And what is your major?
The major is the major area that you study,
the most important area that you study.
The area where you are specialized.
Yeah, the area that you focus on. Okay.
Now we heard another
one that's called a minor.
So this is another
area that you study,
but it is less important than your major.
Okay, so major and your minor.
So let's give an example.
Imagine you must
take 100 classes to
graduate from university.
Mm-hmm. Maybe you have to take 50
for your major and maybe 30 for your minor.
Okay, very good. And
now on your degree on your
title, does it say what is
your major and minor?
Well, I think it depends on the university,
but in my case, yes. Okay, very good.
So major and minor. Now
related to this and what you are
saying about your classes,
it takes us to our next
word, which is
credits, credits, credits.
Now, this is easily confused
with classes sometimes.
That's right. Well, a
credit is kind of a point.
So like maybe, so in
university, you need a
certain number of credits
or points to graduate.
Okay, so suppose you
need 100 credits to graduate.
So that's not 100 courses
because each course
might be worth four
or six or eight credits,
depending on how
important it is. Very good.
So maybe the classes
that are part of your major
will have more credits.
All right, very good.
So and now we have our
last word in this dialogue
and it was tuition tuition.
She had to pay her tuition.
So tuition is the money that
you must pay for education.
Okay, only for education.
That's right. So
university tuition, private
school tuition, or even
language course tuition.
Okay, so a tuition is the money
you must pay for school only.
Yep. So we've seen a lot
of great words used for
registering at university.
So I think it's time
to listen to the dialogue
for the second time a
little bit slower and
then we'll come back and
take a look at some
phrases. Excuse me.
Is this where I register?
I'd like to sign up for my
courses for next
semester. Yes, of course.
I need your student ID please.
Here you are. Okay, Susan,
it says here that you are a business
major and that you're in your second year.
Is this information correct?
Yes. I do want to take some
additional credits this year
to get a minor in psychology.
Sure, that's not a problem.
Do you have a list of courses
that you want to take this semester?
Yeah, here's my
list. I'm not sure if
the class schedule allowed
me to take all of them, though.
Yeah, that's perfect.
What about the
subjects for your minor?
Oh yeah, I almost forgot.
I need to take fundamental
linguistics, consumer
psychology, and neuroanatomy.
Wow, you're going to be
busy this semester.
Okay, here you go.
You're registered now. You
have to make your first tuition
payment before classes
start. All right, so it's
time for putting it
together, putting it together.
And we're going to
look at some phrases here
that we can use to talk
about education and
university and we can
use them in different ways.
All right, and our
first phrase is actually
very similar to register
to sign up for something.
Okay, I want to sign
up for. I'd like to sign
up for my courses. I think
it would be a good idea
if we'd listen to some
examples of how we can use
this phrase. Example
one. I signed up for a one
year gym membership.
Example two. If you want
to assist our meeting,
you need to sign up first.
Example three. I hate
signing up for things
online because they just
send you spam emails.
Okay, so I can see that
to sign up for something
is to agree to take
part in it. Okay, so it's
a little bit more
informal than register.
Yeah, exactly. Less formal.
All right, so moving on
to our second phrase. This is very important
because it's often used improperly.
Yeah, people often make
mistakes with this phrase.
All right, so let's look at
this phrase second year.
So she is in her second year.
Now, it seems very simple.
So why are we explaining
this? Well, it often
gets confused with grade.
So when we talk about
university, we talk about
first year, second year,
third year, fourth year.
We cannot say grade one,
grade two, grade three, grade
four, or year one, year two.
No, it's always first year, second year,
third year, fourth year. Okay, very good.
Or last year. Yeah, last
year, my last year of college.
Exactly. Very good. So
so now you know how you
can explain to someone
what year of college or
university you're
in. Yes, that's right.
Very good. And we have
one more phrase to you. And it
was when she was
getting her class schedule.
So class schedule, class
schedule. Now, a schedule
is the list of things you
do at what time? Right.
So it's the timetable of
your day or your week.
Yep. All right. And
your class schedule will
say all the classes that you
have and what time they're at.
So what other types of
schedules can we have?
You also have maybe
a gym schedule.
That's right. Or even
a work schedule. Right.
So we have different
types of schedules.
And you can use it depending
on what you're doing.
Those are all the phrases we
have for putting it together today.
And now let's listen to the dialogue for
the last time. And then we'll come back.
Excuse me. Is this
where I register?
I'd like to sign up for my
courses for next semester.
Yes, of course. I need
your student ID please.
Here you are. Okay.
Susan. It says here that
you're a business major and
that you're in your second year.
Is this information
correct? Yes.
I do want to take some
additional credits this
year to get a minor
in psychology. Sure.
That's not a problem. Do
you have a list of courses that
you want to take this
semester? Yeah. Here's my list.
I'm not sure if the class schedule
allowed me to take all of them though.
Yeah. That's perfect. What
about the subjects for your minor?
Oh yeah. I almost forgot.
I need to take fundamental
linguistics, consumer
psychology, and neuroanatomy.
Wow. You're going to be
busy this semester.
Okay. Here you go.
You're registered now. You
have to make your first tuition
payment before
classes start. All right.
So we were talking about
second year, first year,
third year, et cetera. Yeah. Now there are
also other names that we give to each year,
both for high
school and university.
And I think this is only for
America, like in the United States.
We don't do this in Canada
and I always get so confused.
So Marco, what is the name you give
to first year students? Okay. So first year
students are called freshmen.
Okay. Because they're
fresh because they're
fresh. Yeah. They just came
from middle school. They
just came from high school.
All right. And what about
the second year students?
They're called sophomores.
Okay. Because they're
soft. It's not soft.
It's soft more like this.
Oh, pH. Soft more. Soft
more. And then third year
students are called juniors.
Okay. Because they're
almost the, let's like
junior manager. Exactly.
Because then last year
students are called seniors.
So the oldest guys
in the school. Exactly.
So you can say, yeah, I'm a
sophomore at Arizona State University.
Okay. So we only use this
in America though, right?
Yes, yes. It's very, and not only for
university, but also for high school. Okay.
All right, guys. That's all
the time we have for today.
I hope you enjoyed this
lesson. And if you have
any questions or comments,
or you want to share
with us your experiences
in high school or
university, please come to
the website at englishpot.
com. That's right. So
Marco and I are there to
answer your questions. And until next time,
thanks for listening and goodbye. Bye.